<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joanna Chin | Portfolio</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:8080</link>
    <description>Portfolio site for Joanna Chin - interaction designer &amp; creative technologist</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Craigslist for Brokers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/06-craigslistforbrokers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/06-craigslistforbrokers/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Craigslist for Brokers&lt;/i&gt; is a design concept for creating a real estate broker’s companion application for rental postings on craigslist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complete competition analysis revealed that while there are companies out there with apps intended to help real estate brokers and their teams, ultimately many of these are hard to navigate, do not integrate with craigslist, and don’t directly address the new challenges of multi-channel communication with clients that face brokers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to figure out the core activities for a young, somewhat tech-savvy real estate broker in Manhattan, where high-demand neighborhoods may produce 1,000+ responses per day, I spoke with several brokers and mapped out the entire retail process from acquiring &amp;amp; negotiating details of service and posting an ad to scheduling, final logistics, and follow-up. From these I pulled out six core activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_coreactivities.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because some of these are needs are fulfilled already by craigslist or other competitor apps, I pulled out managing customer communications as one place with potential for more innovation in order to improve organization of clients and speed of response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mapping out a broker’s possible journey through an app for specific tasks associated with client management showed me places where a user might want quick access to a specific client or property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel carousel-slider&quot; data-indicators=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#one!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_userjourney1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#two!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_userjourney2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#three!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_userjourney3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After observing and speaking with several brokers, I also noted that part of their challenge was the multitude of ways that a client could communicate with them - even just keeping track of emails, texts, and automated messages from real estate online posting sites was difficult. To deal with the volume of responses that often required automated or similar responses, I incorporated some simple AI to determine when an automated script could be selected for a response, while still giving the broker the ability to customize the message if need be. Boiled down, these needs became the core features for my app design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_corefeatures.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to mockup the proposed application with these core features, I first sketched out general screen flows, created some quick digital wireframes, and designed the final user interface designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_sketches.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_wires.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;craigslist_UI.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Craigslist for Brokers&lt;/i&gt; was created in response to a design challenge for Moment design studio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post from the Past</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/01-postfromthepast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/01-postfromthepast/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Post from the Past (PFTP)&lt;/i&gt; is an immersive in-home experience in which you receive physical packages from historical figures in order to uncover the mystery of their personal story online. Hear their voices, explore artifacts from their life, and search our digital archives to fit together the multi-media puzzle pieces that reveal their story. PFTP originated during (and won) a design jam for A+E History Channel. It was also a 2016 NYC Media Lab Combine (a pre-accelerator program for tech &amp;amp; media startups) selectee and New Challenge Winner, which provided the structure for &lt;a href=&quot;#business&quot;&gt;proving out the business&lt;/a&gt; and social impact aspects of the project. An &lt;a href=&quot;#exhibition&quot;&gt;installation&lt;/a&gt; showing the user journey was designed for the 2016 MFA Design &amp;amp; Technology thesis show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lack of engagement and meaningful learning of history in pre-college education and a limited number of avenues for continued enrichment post-college graduation. As the humanities continue to lose prestige and resources in the pre-college education system, there is a danger that the knowledge and critical thinking skills developed through rigorous history instruction will be lost in future generations. Furthermore, in many classrooms history is communicated through reading textbooks focusing on “Great White Man History” and the recitation of dates and absolute facts, which do not provide for deeper/connected learning of historical concepts and also do nothing to create connected or enthusiastic lifelong learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post from the Past seeks to make learning history a more accessible, authentic, and engaging experience. Using game mechanics, we are attempting to mimic and train current and future generations around how to do research - sifting through information, filtering and synthesizing primary and secondary sources, and using critical thinking skills to draw their own informed conclusions about contested historical events. Furthermore, we aim to build a sustainable business that will enable us to advance this social mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Product Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of Post from the Past has been through several stages of product development: design sprint for the A+E History Channel, a 4-month research, business validation, and product development phase with the NYC Media Lab Combine, and our current phase, which involves 3-week design sprints to further develop and test the digital product. In addition to leading the team and serving as the primary product designer/developer for the second phase, I also created an exhibition to promote our product and process for my MFA Design &amp;amp; Technology thesis show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_brainstorming.JPG&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minimum viable product was conceived and created in less than 24 hours for the A+E History Channel design jam. Collectively, my three teammates and I brainstormed the basic concept, researched its fit within the existing A+E History Channel product ecosystem, and developed a streamlined user experience. We created a physical product, basic web app UI, and a video to capture the narrative experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_main2.gif&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Fabrication &amp;amp; Tech Iterations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the product side, I sourced and fabricated all physical components and developed/tested the tech integration. Fabrication involved reproducing artifacts from the historical figure’s life and sourcing them when possible in order to balance my production time cost and customizability against the cost and authenticity of sourced objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel carousel-slider&quot; data-indicators=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#one!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_box3.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#two!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_papers.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#three!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_fab2.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#four!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_fab3.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#five!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_fab4.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When testing tech solutions to the audio component of the boxes, I sought to balance sound quality, volume, size, consistency of experience, and cost. I tested capacitive touch sensors, light sensor, touchscreen touch patterns, QR codes, and image recognition as a way to trigger the sound and various speaker sizes and amps for audio output. All of this was also weighed against our user experience goals: complete immersion in the tangible experience, delight/surprise, and guidance for how to understand/explore the items in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_tech2.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_tech.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After numerous rounds of testing, I ended up finding a middle ground between the different requirements through one of the simplest solutions: a greeting card sound module with light sensor and speaker hidden under a fake bottom of the box so that when a user opens the box, it plays the introductory audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Content strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with another narrative expert, I crafted the entire story told through the objects included in the mailings, accompanying audio script, and web app. This involved in-depth research into the featured historical person and the time, place(s), and people connected to her. In addition to synthesizing this information into lively first-person narration and creative multi-media pieces, I also mapped out the content flow for the web app, so that we could start to understand possible structures for the digital platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_contentflow.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Digital Product UX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with another UX/UI designer, I created wireframes and developed the latest iteration of UI, integrating the content I created into the final designs for the web app. I incorporated all of these into the prototype for the app (using InVision), and developed the first iteration of the web app after a round of user testing and design revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_uisketch.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_wires.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_UX2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of user testing, in recent months, our team has pivoted our digital product to more closely mirror the physical experience of exploration and to put more emphasis on a game-like experience. In its most recent iteration, the digital component focuses on uncovering pieces of the historical figure’s story by searching keywords and unlocking lines on a crucial redacted file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;User Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each iteration of the physical and digital product, we conducted user testing, putting the product in front of our target users and observing and getting feedback, before synthesizing and incorporating our findings into the next iteration of the product. This was particularly useful for understanding how open-ended or directed the experience should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel carousel-slider&quot; data-indicators=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#one!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_usertesting3.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#two!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_usertesting4.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#three!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_usertesting2.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#four!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_usertesting.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in early testing we found that users needed a clearer path from the physical to digital experience, so we incorporated a postcard from an imaginary “Archivist” that articulated a clear direction/action for the user: &lt;i&gt;Who sent this? Are they guilty? You may find the missing pieces at www.postfromthepast.net&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot; id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business Validation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Research &amp;amp; Customer Segmentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the course of the Combine program, my team and I conducted over 120 interviews to determine audience fit and user experience. For the customer segment interviews, we asked broad questions about behavior patterns (e.g., As a history enthusiast, how do you consume history now? What’s your historical guilty pleasure?) and honed in on specifics within their self-identified interest (e.g. As a museum educator, what type of objects do your students find the most interesting? What are challenges to teaching with objects?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_usertesting.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reached out to and interviewed self-identified history enthusiasts (ranging from historical reenactors to long-time biography readers), museum staff, educators (school administrators and teachers), game enthusiasts/designers, subscription box customers, and parents. This process proved many of our hypotheses about these groups, but there were some surprises about our assumptions as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video summarizing our journey and some high level findings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-YhTu8hyqxQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From these interviews we established that our target customer was a relatively settled adult who is looking for new and more interactive ways to consume topics of interest (that they do not necessarily associate with “hardcore history”). This ideal consumer might also have a child with who they want to share their love to learning and think of PFTP as a way to spend quality time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Business Planning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basing our business validation process in lean startup methodology, we calculated market sizing, explored existing box subscription competitors, created models for sourcing and channel distribution, and figured out the economics of product/marketing cost versus revenue at various price points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel carousel-slider&quot; data-indicators=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#one!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_business1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#two!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_business2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#three!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_business3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#four!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_business4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our pitch, which included business validation and product development during the Combine, was presented to major NYC media companies, VCs, and other investors at the NYC Media Lab Combine Demo Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_presentation.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot; id=&quot;exhibition&quot;&gt;Exhibition Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to present the initial body of work done on Post from the Past, I also designed and implemented an exhibition design that allowed visitors to see the user journey laid out in physical space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;carousel carousel-slider&quot; data-indicators=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#one!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_exhibition.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#two!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_exhibition2.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#three!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_exhibition3.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;carousel-item&quot; href=&quot;#four!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;post_exhibition5.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first iteration was mapped out in the physical space and a second round of exhibition designs were sketched out and then modeled in Illustrator in order to get approval for installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did all of the fabrication and construction for the physical installation. Here’s a peek into the final uncovering of the stenciled large script words that served to ground the piece:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y-R2fNMAUrc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOJO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/03-jojo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/03-jojo/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;JOJO&lt;/i&gt; is a chatbot system that handles questions/requests from customers and streamlines business communications and operations built for a Fortune 500 telecommunications company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To comply with my non-disclosure agreement, I have omitted and obfuscated confidential information in this case study. The information in this case study is my own and does not necessarily reflect the views of my employer/client for this project.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with many big telecommunication companies, this one is just beginning to explore the wide variety of uses for artificial intelligence/machine learning and the ways that it might build on existing assets within their consumer-facing and enterprise business arms. While much of the engineer expertise exists within the business ecosystem, part of the challenge of this emerging technology is crafting concrete use-cases that fit within the existing business goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team’s goal was to come up with and build working prototypes of chatbots that could provide new services and opportunities for the company and its customers/clients. &lt;i&gt;JOJO&lt;/i&gt; is a chatbot system that handles questions/requests from customers and streamlines business communications and operations. The system is built in a modular way, so that the four major components - conversational UI, artificial intelligence, operations dashboard, and analytics - can be pulled out and rearranged for applicability across multiple industries and for many different use-cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jojo_main.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the company’s existing industry connections, we developed JOJO as part of a complete system for the hospitality industry that would augment existing hardware/network sales. In the next few months, we’re aiming to incorporate the system into a small geo-fenced ad campaign for the company’s retail branch, as a way to provide a more active way of getting new customers into nearby Verizon stores. Throughout the development process we sought to tie the bot to existing department’s work and continue to build support for the project internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Product Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product development process incorporated industry and customer research (interviews, observation, and market research surveys), outlining specific use-cases, mapping out the conversation and user experience flows, researching and architecting the technical system, coding and training the scripts for the bot intent recognition and responses, and getting internal buy-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My contribution to the project included a mix of UX design, technical prototyping, and product positioning. I led much of the service design work - creating service blueprints, sequence diagrams, annotated wireframes - as well as the content strategy - crafting dialog trees and structuring the intents and entities in the bot framework. I collaborated with another designer on the visual design of the user interfaces, which included the mobile conversational UI plus a mission control dashboard and an analytics page (for the hospitality vertical). On the technical side, I did a lot of the bot scripting (coding the conversation waterfall and specific bot responses) and training, as well as provided engineering support on the web application front end to our primary tech specialist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYC Data Visualized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/04-nycmayorsoffice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/04-nycmayorsoffice/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These web-based, interactive data visualizations were created for the NYC Mayor’s Office to visualize data from their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.nyc.gov/site/hhsaccelerator/index.page&quot;&gt;HHS Accelerator&lt;/a&gt;. The visualizations were built using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, and the JavaScript InfoVis Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my 2015 summer internship with the NYC Mayor’s Office, I worked to fulfill the design and data visualization needs in the Office of Operations, which is responsible for running and evaluating HHS Accelerator. HHS Accelerator is an online-system designed to improve the City’s contracting process by consolidating access to the city’s funding opportunities (across departments) and providing financial transaction capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My particular goal was to analyze three years-worth of data from HHS Accelerator and visualize it in a way that could be used for internal staff to see the number of pre-qualified providers, RFPs, and groups funded in each service areas, as well as get broader sense of the usefulness of their existing taxonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the process by reading existing documents about HHS Accelerator, exploring how I as a user might journey through its systems, and speaking with in-house designers, policy experts, engineers, and data scientists to understand the needs of the office and its constituents. I analyzed what data had been collected over the last three years since the program’s inception and became to sketch out what aspects might be most useful for the Office of Operations staff and some of major health and human services stakeholders who had helped shaped the initial platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;mayors_sketch.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created paper prototypes, which were shown to a small group of Operation Office stakeholders before quickly creating a version of the interactive visualizations on the web. This first digital prototype was presented in a larger meeting of stakeholders so that they could see how the data might be interacted with on the web and for them to provide input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;mayors_main.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;mayors_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on their feedback and the existing design guidelines for the Accelerator program, I created a new iteration of visualizations that were linked to real datasets, balancing my design and interaction sense with the expressed needs of my clients. This iteration of visualizations was presented to a working group that suggested final tweaks. My final deliverables included the code and documentation about how the data visualizations were structured and rendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;mayors_main2.gif&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banal Chaos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/05-banalchaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/05-banalchaos/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Banal Chaos&lt;/i&gt; is an interactive performance piece in which the audience is invited to sit in chairs arranged like a NYC subway car and don headphones to listen in on the inner thoughts of strangers via a mobile web app. Performers silently embody the strangers going about their daily transit routine creating both a shared and individual performance experience and pseudo-game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;banalchaos_other3.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prompt/problem for &lt;i&gt;Banal Chaos&lt;/i&gt; was more about methodology, process, and implementation than product, business, or user concerns. As a performance/installation piece conceptualized and actualized within a 24-hour period of time, the team was forced to explore differences of cross-discipline creative process, unknown variables regarding presentation, and diverse expectations about the final outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team’s goal was to create a performative response to the prompt, “banal chaos,” that was flexible enough to work for a single large group performance or groups filtering in and out of the performance space. We wanted to use tech in a way that was supported and reflected the underlying themes of the piece in an essential rather than auxiliary way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with a group of five to develop the concept and create basic user flow. The team, which was comprised of one film artist, an actor, a director, a playwright, and myself, had to work to develop a way of working together that took aspects of both design and theatre creative process. We learned quickly that individuals had very different views on process and product and that establishing a common ground of practice was essential to moving forward. We did quick individual brainstorming sessions and shared concepts with one another, building off of each other’s ideas and focusing on common themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We settled on developing a piece around conversations and sounds on the subway (which are banal amidst the chaos of public transportation in NYC). As the technical and interaction expert on the team, I suggested that we draw from shared experiences and common interactions on the subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final piece played with the everyday actions that we use in the subway - listening in on conversations, getting lost in internal thought, and putting on headphones - to explore and subvert those actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;banalchaos_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience brought their own mobile devices and headphones into the space and were invited to use them to access a web app through which they could listen to pre-recorded conversations and internal monologues from passengers. Audience members could choose “chaos” (to listen to all the conversations simultaneously) or to listen to one conversation at a time and switch between the characters; user choice was a crucial piece of the experience. The audio experience was grounded by subway sounds (recorded by one of my teammates) that played on speakers in the shared performance space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;banalchaos_screen2.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, performers pantomimed the characters who are having the conversations/internal monologues. This created a situation in which audience members had to engage in order to connect what they were seeing with what they were listening to. In this way we created a piece that examines performance as a personalized experience and as a game (with audience members trying to guess which stranger’s conversation they were listening in on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;banalchaos_other.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Technical Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a quick turn-around time, I developed and deployed the mobile web app for the project. The app is built using HTML, CSS, javascript and contains audio components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;banalchaos_screen3.JPG&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>d.bot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/07-dbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/07-dbot/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;D.bot&lt;/i&gt; is a chatbot that draws from female experiences in dating to simulates conversing with an unenlightened male. The project is intended to address in a light-hearted, humorous way, the pervasiveness of gender stereotypes and the ease with which disrespectful and patronizing comments find their way into everyday conversation. It was featured in &lt;i&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Refinery29&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;MTV News&lt;/i&gt;, and other feminist and/or tech blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women are harassed both in real life and online. We know this is a problem because when we were creating &lt;i&gt;d.bot&lt;/i&gt;, a feminist dating site, Bumble, had just come onto the scene. Bumble sought to break traditional gender roles (of who pursues who) and create a “safer” space based on “online accountability and kindness.” The traction it has gained since then seems to indicate the need for new solutions to the problem of harassment based on gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than focus on lack of safe space, we saw one of the big challenges of gender-based harassment as understanding the relationship between the benign, well-intentioned gendered comments that many men make and the truly chauvinistic and recognizably egregious ones. There is no easy way to say to a male colleague or friend that their casual sexist comments and actions are still perpetuating a culture in which women are not treated equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an interaction standpoint, the goal with d.bot was to create an experience in which the user continues to engage with something despite not wanting to. From a social change standpoint, we were interested in a creating a bot that was both comedic in its responses, but also ran the gamut of sexist and racist comments from more benign to outrageously insulting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final bot draws from a database of responses derived from women’s actual interactions in online and offline dating. Users are encouraged to add their own experiences to the bot’s AI, so that it can continue to reflect the latest in insensitive and insulting comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;d.bot_other1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the technical learning of how to make a simple chatbot, &lt;i&gt;d.bot&lt;/i&gt; was fundamental in exploring some major aspects of crafting artificial intelligence that relate closely to shaping user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“I knew it was a bot, and it still made me so mad!”
&lt;br&gt;-comment from anonymous user&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the bot was built using “simple AI” (i.e., exact responses for specific trigger words rather than using algorithms to determine natural language patterns), the context of the bot and the users’ interactions with him were key to a successful interactive experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, because he is positioned as a “douche bot,” the user immediately excuses slightly off responses because, like a real jerk, he’s not actually listening to you most of the time. Second, the content of the chat, similar to what you might experience on an online dating site, provides some context and direction for the conversation because we know what kind of topics are discussed when you are trying to suss out another person’s personality and intent. Third, we sought to examine the premise of the Turing Test, which is the measuring stick by which the humanness of a machine. It seems that the test assumes that best of what humanness is rather than the very faults that make us unresponsive, rude, and illogical. &lt;i&gt;D.bot&lt;/i&gt;, like Microsoft’s infamous racist twitter bot, poses the opposite, that these flaws actually make the bot experience more human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;d.bot_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed z-depth-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on feedback from early users, we modified &lt;i&gt;d.bot&lt;/i&gt; to include responses to users’ actions as well as the content of their responses. For example, in the latest iteration, the bot will comment if a user takes too long to respond (e.g., “Are you ghosting me?”) and also has some special responses if a user is too curt (repeated short responses) or too verbose (words larger than X characters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;D.bot&lt;/i&gt; was created in collaboration with Bryan Collinsworth. I took the lead on the experience design, web development, and content curation. The bot was built using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, node.js, socket.io, and a Parse database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAMA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/02-lama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/02-lama/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;LAMA&lt;/i&gt; was developed for the Publicis Groupe “Retail Experience of the Future” NYC Media Lab Corporate Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic concept is an app that stores users’ shopping lists so that when they visit a big box store, the app can automatically route them on the most efficient path to shop for their items, dynamically changing their path as the customer adds items to their Smart Cart or list. Because items are being check off as they are added to the Smart Cart, users can checkout at any time using the app on their phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For flagship stores, navigation data could be reflected in a light installation on the ceiling of the store adding visual interest to an otherwise mundane shopping process. Retailers also benefit by being able to add location-/user-specific ads, receive the data from consumer product choices, and visualize overall store traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E-commerce is draining sales from brick and mortar stores. It is convenient and helps consumers avoid the stress of navigating a store and the time suck of waiting in line for checkout. However, there are some definite reasons why customers still sometimes chose to shop in-store - the experience of browsing, the ability to see and touch physical products, and being able to get a product immediately to name a few. Looking to the future of retail, how might the in-store shopping experience be informed by e-commerce platforms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the tight timeline for the design process, our goal was to form a coherent and innovative solution to the problems facing in-store retail and to pitch a concept that had been tested with users and proven from a technical perspective. Our solution, LAMA not only addresses the pain points for brick and mortar customer experience at a “big box store” by incorporating successful aspects of e-commerce platforms, but also incorporates features that provide value for the retailer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our process for developing LAMA involved four major stages: research and synthesis of existing trends and new technology, ideation, rapid prototyping, quick user testing in the physical space, and refining the concept and interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team of three, guided by designer Bernardo Schorr (Smart Design), developed LAMA by first researching examples of forward thinking in retail and interactive spaces. We synthesized over 40 examples to identify overarching trends and analyzed what about these were successful and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Digital Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we brainstormed a concept, I led the development of a holistic user journey through the physical and digital space and developed the pitch narrative. Working with another UX/UI designer, I created the final consumer-facing screen designs and made the interactive prototype in InVision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lama_UX.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;User Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a week’s time, the team conducted two rounds of in-depth user testing on-site at a “big box store” with four participants. In order to get a sense of the physical aspects of the concept, we used yarn to simulate the lighted path to items on the consumer’s list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lama_usertesting2.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lama_usertesting1.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lama_usertesting3.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel to our user testing and proving out the product concept, our software developer on the project built technical mockups to test the feasibility of multiple user pathways via a custom algorithm. The final concept was presented to executives and staff of Publicis Groupe subsidiaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lama_presentation.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between the Beats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/08-betweenthebeats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/08-betweenthebeats/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Between the Beats&lt;/i&gt; is a short motion graphics piece created for a fictional music channel that delivers “music to get you in the mood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with style frames, I established three distinct visual styles and vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;btb_other.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After deciding on an aesthetic direction based on user testing the readability of each of these designs, I created a storyboard to articulate and flesh out the visual style and start to encapsulate the motion and transition design as well. I drew from Blue Note records cover art as one major source of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;btb_storyboard.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final motion graphics piece was done in After Effects and pushes the idea of music hidden under clothing and in the spaces in between to highlight the unique edgy and irreverent personality of this sexy music channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This piece was shown as part of a projection piece at the Parsons Fashion Gala (2016).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Room 1206</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/11-room1206/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/11-room1206/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Room 1206&lt;/i&gt; is an exploratory narrative game in which players play a hotel housekeeper responsible for cleaning the same hotel room every day. As players complete their daily tasks, they encounter the signs and remnants of the guests who are staying there. Personal items, photographs, “garbage” left behind. Some mundane; some hinting at secrets, scandals, the triumphs and failures of human life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;room1206_other.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was created with an interest in creating tension between a desire to uncover narrative and the ethics required of a housekeeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;room1206_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;room1206_main.gif&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is built in Unity in collaboration with Bryan Collinsworth. For this project, I built 3D models using Rhino and Maya and crafted many of the player and object interactions. &lt;i&gt;Room 1206&lt;/i&gt; was demoed at the NYC Arcade (2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of an early asset and interaction test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mV5ck72Ubuk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later my teammate built on this narrative premise to create a VR experience using Unreal Engine and HTC Vive during a fellowship with Viacom. It was showcased at a Viacom Next Demo Day (August 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;VR.JPG&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this iteration, the player is not necessarily the housekeeper; the player’s role in the game/narrative remains ambiguous throughout. The experience focuses on the immersive quality of the virtual reality platform, as well as the compelling narrative told through the items left behind rather than the ethical quandaries of digging through someone’s personal items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/86cJoypqFew&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>in a word</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/09-inaword/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/09-inaword/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brief opening credits for the play, &lt;i&gt;in a word&lt;/i&gt; (by Lauren Yee) directed and performed by students in The New School drama department. Animations were hand-drawn and the motion design was done in After Effects.&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;inaword_other.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;inaword_other2.png&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wag It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/10-wagit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/10-wagit/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wag It&lt;/i&gt; is a virtual reality game in which one plays a dog searching for love and attention by wagging her tail (i.e., shaking her butt). A player dons an Oculus Rift and uses a mobile device placed in her back pocket to measure wagging motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;wagit_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inspiration, I drew from current critiques of VR, using the player’s blindness/isolation in the headset as a way to provide entertainment not only for the primary user but also those around her. A related impetus for this project was the challenge of creating a scenario in which a person would willingly act a little ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;wagit_other.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wag It&lt;/i&gt; is built in Unity 5 and the game environment is connected to a web endpoint in order to continuously pull a mobile device’s accelerometer data. The endpoint was built using JavaScript and node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was developed as part of the 2016 Intel Kill Screen Scholars program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RentersRATE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/articles/12-rentersrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8080/articles/12-rentersrate/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;RentersRATE&lt;/i&gt; is an app and SMS system that crowdsources tenant feedback for safer and healthier living. The app allows NYC tenants to submit reports about problems in their building or apartment in order to hold landlords and building management companies more accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half of NYC’s residents are renters, including many of the city’s most economically insecure people. Unsafe and unhealthy living conditions are shockingly common: in 2014, NYC’s 200 worst buildings had over 4,300 immediately hazardous violations, according to the Department of Housing Preservation and Development. Limited city enforcement resources and huge landlord-tenant power differentials leave many renters with few effective ways to expose and address issues like faulty utilities, infestations, crumbling infrastructure or financial exploitation that can put their health, wellbeing and livelihood at risk. Tenants often don’t even know if fellow residents are experiencing similar issues. In an era of enormous income inequality, it’s crucial to empower renters to report serious problems and build communities and networks of accountability to get them addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My collaborator and I were developing rentersRATE for the 2015 New Challenge, a competition to fund ideas that address today’s social and environmental challenges. We had about 3 months to conduct our entire design process, pitch our product concept, and go through two rounds of feedback and iteration. Judging was based on innovation of solution, team qualifications, partnerships with relevant people/groups working in the space, and likelihood of implementation and social impact. With RentersRATE we were focused on creating a platform that would empower tenants, hold landlords and housing management companies accountable, and provide a place for NYC government workers to check and flag problems or see big housing trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;project-sub-main&quot;&gt;Product Design Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our process for developing &lt;i&gt;RentersRATE&lt;/i&gt; involved four major stages: research, ideation, prototyping, feedback and iteration. Particularly because our goal was to provide a platform that empowered NYC tenants, we were particularly cognizant of centering our design process and product around our users’ needs and familiar digital interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Research &amp;amp; Ideation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the research stage of the project, we spoke with NYC renters and housing rights activists in order to better understand the problem and existing solutions. We found that current systems are largely limited to city housing authorities relying on inspections and enforcement within tough budget constraints; tenant advocacy organizations doing strong work but lacking a substantial digital footprint, and web platforms like Zillow that focus more on owners than renters. The city has NYC311, which allows residents to submit complaint and check its status either online or through an app, but ultimately, this still puts the onus on city staff and municipal workers to follow through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We developed &lt;i&gt;RentersRATE&lt;/i&gt; to fill this niche for a digital product that enables tenants to take direct action using technologies they already have (SMS, web, and app-enabled mobile phones). We were particularly influenced by the lack of connectedness and solidarity as barriers to renters’ rights, and drew from other successful social feedback models (e.g. Yelp for dining, TripAdvisor for travel, Amazon reviews for products) in order to bring this crowdsourced feedback model to housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary role in prototyping was developing the UX/UI design and testing the user flow with an InVision. Because of the interest in making this product accessible to a wide range of NYC tenant populations, I spent time mapping out the user experience beyond the screen, including how a user with a flip-phone might use SMS for reporting. Two of the biggest challenges in designing this user experience were balancing anonymity versus information sharing and how to simplify the user journey as much as possible while still achieving the app’s primary goals. In scoping the project, we made a conscious choice to focus primarily on fleshing out tenants’ interactions (while keeping the landlords’ and government workers’ purpose for accessing the app as part of the larger framing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;rentersrate_other2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;rentersrate_other.jpg&quot; class=&quot;materialboxed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;project-sub&quot;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first iteration of the concept was publish on the New Challenge website and the general public was invited to give their input, while the selection committee gave specific feedback on the viability of the concept and proposed implementation from our application. As a result of these comments, my collaborator and I revised both our framing of the idea, and reached out to additional housing policy and advocacy experts. As a result of feedback from all of these sources, we did a second iteration of the prototype, which included a page after a user reported a problem that pulled up specific action items that they could take right now - from a government webpage to find out more about the specific policy around their complaint to municipal departments to call directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>